{
    "id": "95c7d5e7777c42478e9c1fd8832b8951",
    "title": "Tenses worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Don’t disturb me. I ....................... my homework.",
            "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about actions and situations that are happening at the moment of speaking. ",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "am doing",
                "did"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d2b3edc04cb848259464105c697826d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘Where is John?’ ‘He ………………….. out five minutes ago.’",
            "description": "To say that something happened at a particular point of time in the past, we use the past simple tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ce7a27519bb546ada91caf7021eb7eba"
        },
        {
            "question": "The baby ...................... since morning.",
            "description": "To talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present, we use the present perfect continuous tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "cries",
                "has been crying"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9377307262f242eba1db4623156db407"
        },
        {
            "question": "My son ..................... to be a doctor.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about our likes, preferences, needs and wants. ",
            "answers": [
                "want",
                "wants",
                "is wanting",
                "has wanted"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "631d989b180d4a1abab1de9dc18a21a9"
        },
        {
            "question": "The soup …………………. awful.",
            "description": "Taste is one of those verbs that are not normally used in the continuous form. ",
            "answers": [
                "tastes",
                "is tasting",
                "taste"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7a28c170b04349759af6f50250859a14"
        },
        {
            "question": "I ....................... him at the club yesterday.",
            "description": "The present perfect tense cannot be used with past time adverbs like yesterday or last year. ",
            "answers": [
                "meet",
                "met",
                "have met"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "885cc336a7e747029a25b7fdb0f0cf4c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He used to visit us every week, but now he .......................",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts and habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "rarely comes",
                "is rarely coming",
                "has rarely come"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ca2210aba34249b1a4646e20416a6765"
        },
        {
            "question": "The guests ..................... they are sitting in the garden.",
            "description": "Present perfect is the most common tense for giving news of recent events. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrived",
                "have arrived",
                "are arriving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4a32c87b37e243a38cfd288657e9cc0d"
        },
        {
            "question": "I know every scene in that film because I ..................... it several times.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about a past event whose effect is still felt in the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bf8839aa27bd4976bc6511fff7bef9d8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have a friend who .......................... in a pub.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is working",
                "works",
                "work"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "544c0bc5c5824695a0a70e10fd6a0857"
        }
    ]
}